By default, NULL values are allowed
in columns when tables are created.
However, often when creating a table, one or
more columns should be required to have values.
Take a look at this CREATE TABLE statement. This
command is similar to one we ran elsewhere in the
course, but I am now about to create a test
version of the BikeRepairs table we created,
and let's look at which columns should not
be null. BikeRepairID should be required,
and it should be the primary key of this table,
so I have added the words NOT NULL PRIMARY KEY
to this column. CustomerID should not be null
either. The rest of these fields are debatable
as we may not know these fields upon creating a
repair. One could argue that the estimated rate
field should be required so that a customer
has an idea of how much a repair will cost.
I have added NOT NULL to that column as well.
I will then create this table and execute
this command. That worked. What if, however, we
determine later that the estimated rate column can
be left blank? An ALTER command will work, setting
the column to allow nulls. I will type the ALTER
TABLE command needed to do this and notice
that we need to specify the data type again.
In other words, treat the syntax here as if this
is a brand new column even though it is not.
I will run just this portion of the query
window, and we have a successful result.